

# Timothy Cohen

FRONT-END DESIGNER

## **PROFILE**

Experience in creating aesthetic and responsive websites using modern technologies (e.g HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS).

Creative background in the audiovisual field. Professional photographer and travel writer with work published in National Geographic, Lonely Planet and several travel medias.

Excel in understanding, communicating and effectively interacting with people across cultures.

Hold dual nationalities - United States and Belgium.

# CONTACT

PHONE:

+32 493 08 37 94

EMAIL

timothy.cohen@hotmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/timdavhen/

# HOBBIES

Outdoors, CrossFit, Photography, Solo travel. Coffee, Music, Mobile tech

## LANGUAGES

Fluent in French, English, Spanish and Portuguese Basic in Dutch and Italian

## **PORTFOLIO**

https://www.timothycohen.dev

# **EDUCATION**

#### LE WAGON - CODING BOOTCAMP

Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

Acclaimed worldwide coding bootcamp

## ARTS<sup>2</sup> - ÉCOLE SUPÉRIEUR DES ARTS

Sept 2009 - June 2014

• Master's Degree in Applied and Interactive Music

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## LE WAGON - WEB DEVELOPMENT

Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

- Intensive 24-week coding bootcamp to be trained as a Full Stack Web Developer with specialisation in Front-End.
- Artsouille Responsible for providing the visual design and creating a collaborative platform for emerging artists (see websites section) using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku, ActiveRecord, and Ruby on Rails.
- Rent-a-Planet Responsible for conceptualising a creative website (within a timespan of two weeks) that replicates the functionality of a rental platform (see websites section). HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL, git, GitHub, Heroku, Ajax, and Ruby on Rails.

## LE COMPTOIR DE MATHILDE - STORE MANAGER

2019 - 2021

- Responsible for sales, customer satisfaction, inventory management, and for creating financial plan to meet the annual sales target.
- Managing team of ten resources and ensuring the professional development through training, performance appraisal and providing feedback during recruitment.

## THALYS - STEWARD

2017 - 2018

 Responsible for continually improving and developing the onboard experience of customers.

In parallel, I have fueled my creativity by collaborating with **Lonely Planet** as a content travel writer/photographer and got my work displayed in the World Bank headquarters after having been on assignment on **National Geographic**'s collaborative platform.

# SKILLS

Leadership, creativity, **Lightroom**, **Photoshop**, customer centricity, team management, communication, sales